<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<catalog>
    <movie id="mv1">
        <title>The Godfather Part I</title>
        <director>Francis Ford Coppola</director>
        <length>175</length>
        <rating>9.2</rating>
        <year>1972</year>
        <image>../images/mv1.jpg</image>
        <alt>Man in Tuxedo, looks into the distance with one hand raised.</alt>
        <blurb>The Godfather is a 1972 American crime film directed by Francis Ford Coppola, who co-wrote the screenplay with Mario Puzo, based on Puzo's best-selling 1969 novel of the same name.
         The film stars Marlon Brando, Al Pacino, James Caan, Richard Castellano, Robert Duvall, Sterling Hayden, John Marley, Richard Conte, and Diane Keaton.
          It is the first installment in The Godfather trilogy, chronicling the Corleone family under patriarch Vito Corleone (Brando) from 1945 to 1955.
           It focuses on the transformation of his youngest son, Michael Corleone (Pacino), from reluctant family outsider to ruthless mafia boss. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Godfather</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv2">
        <title>The Godfather Part II</title>
        <director>Francis Ford Coppola</director>
        <length>202</length>
        <rating>9</rating>
        <year>1974</year>
        <image>../images/mv2.jpg</image>
        <alt>Man in suit, sitting on a couch looking forward with a serious look</alt>
        <blurb>The Godfather Part II is a 1974 American epic crime film produced and directed by Francis Ford Coppola. 
        The film is partially based on the 1969 novel The Godfather by Mario Puzo, who co-wrote the screenplay with Coppola. 
        Part II serves as both a sequel and a prequel to the 1972 film The Godfather, presenting parallel dramas: one picks up the 1958 story of Michael Corleone (Al Pacino),
         the new Don of the Corleone family, protecting the family business in the aftermath of an attempt on his life; the prequel covers the journey of his father, Vito Corleone (Robert De Niro), 
         from his Sicilian childhood to the founding of his family enterprise in New York City.
          The ensemble cast also features Robert Duvall, Diane Keaton, Talia Shire, Morgana King, John Cazale, Mariana Hill, and Lee Strasberg. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Godfather_Part_II</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv3">
        <title>Goodfellas</title>
        <director>Martin Scorsese</director>
        <length>146</length>
        <rating>8.7</rating>
        <year>1990</year>
        <image>../images/mv3.jpg</image>
        <alt>Three men in suits look directly forward, superimposed on image of an injured/dead man laying on the street</alt>
        <blurb>Goodfellas (stylized GoodFellas) is a 1990 American biographical crime film directed by Martin Scorsese, written by Nicholas Pileggi
         and Scorsese, and produced by Irwin Winkler. It is a film adaptation of the 1985 nonfiction book Wiseguy by Pileggi. Starring Robert De Niro, Ray Liotta, Joe Pesci, Lorraine Bracco
          and Paul Sorvino, the film narrates the rise and fall of mob associate Henry Hill
         and his friends and family from 1955 to 1980. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goodfellas</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv4">
        <title>Heat</title>
        <director>Michael Mann</director>
        <length>170</length>
        <rating>8.3</rating>
        <year>1995</year>
        <image>../images/mv4.jpg</image>
        <alt>Man holding an M16 Rifle transposed on background of two men</alt>
        <blurb>Heat is a 1995 American crime drama film written and directed by Michael Mann.
         It features an ensemble cast led by Al Pacino and Robert De Niro, with Tom Sizemore,
          Jon Voight, and Val Kilmer in supporting roles.
           The film follows the conflict between an LAPD detective, played by Pacino, and a career
            thief, played by De Niro, while also depicting its effect on their professional relationships and personal lives. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_(1995_film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv5">
        <title>Casino</title>
        <director>Martin Scorsese</director>
        <length>178</length>
        <rating>8.2</rating>
        <year>1996</year>
        <image>../images/mv5.jpg</image>
        <alt>Two men in suits look towards the camera with serious looks,
         one holds two die, a woman looks up with a confused expression</alt>
        <blurb>Casino is a 1995 American epic crime film directed by Martin Scorsese,
         produced by Barbara De Fina and distributed by Universal Pictures.
          It is based on the 1995 nonfiction book Casino: Love and Honor in Las Vegas by Nicholas Pileggi, who also co-wrote
           the screenplay along with Scorsese. It stars Robert De Niro,
           Sharon Stone, Joe Pesci, Don Rickles, Kevin Pollak and James Woods.
         The film was the eighth collaboration between director Scorsese and De Niro. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Casino_(1995_film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv6">
        <title>American Gangster</title>
        <director>Ridley Scott</director>
        <length>157</length>
        <rating>7.8</rating>
        <year>2007</year>
        <image>../images/mv6.jpg</image>
        <alt>Two men in suits stand in a full body portrait, one holds a gun,
         both faces are obscured</alt>
        <blurb>American Gangster is a 2007 American biographical crime film directed and produced by Ridley Scott and 
        written by Steven Zaillian. The film is fictionally based on the criminal career of
         Frank Lucas, a gangster from La Grange, North Carolina who smuggled heroin into the United States on American service
          planes returning from the Vietnam War, before being detained by a task force led by detective Richie Roberts.
           The film stars Denzel Washington and Russell Crowe with co-stars Ted Levine, John Ortiz, Josh Brolin,
         Chiwetel Ejiofor, Norman Reedus, Ruby Dee, Lymari Nadal and Cuba Gooding Jr. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/American_Gangster_(film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv7">
        <title>Once Upon a Time in America</title>
        <director>Sergio Leone</director>
        <length>251</length>
        <rating>8.3</rating>
        <year>1984</year>
        <image>../images/mv7.jpg</image>
        <alt>In the foreground five kids walk in the street, in the backgound is the broklyn bridge</alt>
        <blurb>Once Upon a Time in America (Italian: C'era una volta in America) is a 1984 epic crime
         film co-written and directed by Italian filmmaker Sergio Leone and starring 
         Robert De Niro and James Woods. The film is an Italian–American venture produced by The Ladd Company,
          Embassy International Pictures, PSO Enterprises, and Rafran Cinematografica, and distributed by
           Warner Bros. Based on Harry Grey's novel The Hoods, it chronicles the lives of best friends David "Noodles" Aaronson and Maximilian "Max" Bercovicz 
           as they lead a group of Jewish ghetto youths who rise to prominence as Jewish gangsters in New York City's world of organized crime.
            The film explores themes of childhood friendships, love, lust, greed, betrayal, loss,
         broken relationships, together with the rise of mobsters in American society. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Once_Upon_a_Time_in_America</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv8">
        <title>Scarface</title>
        <director>Brian De Palma</director>
        <length>170</length>
        <rating>8.3</rating>
        <year>1983</year>
        <image>../images/mv8.jpg</image>
        <alt>Man in white 1970s style suit holds a pistol while looking at the ground</alt>
        <blurb>Scarface is a 1983 American crime drama film directed by Brian De Palma 
        and written by Oliver Stone. Loosely based on the 1929 novel of the same name and
         serving as a loose remake of the 1932 film, it tells the story of Cuban refugee
          Tony Montana (Al Pacino), who arrives penniless in Miami during the Mariel boatlift
           and becomes a powerful and extremely homicidal drug lord. The film co-stars Steven Bauer, Michelle Pfeiffer,
           Mary Elizabeth Mastrantonio and Robert Loggia. De Palma dedicated this version
         of Scarface to the writers of the original film, Howard Hawks and Ben Hecht</blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Scarface_(1983_film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv9">
        <title>King of New York</title>
        <director>Abel Ferrara</director>
        <length>103</length>
        <rating>6.9</rating>
        <year>1990</year>
        <image>../images/mv9.jpg</image>
        <alt>A man and a woman look out a window in a high rise building</alt>
        <blurb>King of New York is a 1990 neo-noir gangster film directed by Abel Ferrara and written by
         Nicholas St. John. It stars Christopher Walken as a New York City drug kingpin rebuilding his 
         criminal empire after his release from prison, while also attempting to go legitimate. Laurence Fishburne,
          David Caruso, Victor Argo and Wesley Snipes co-star, with supporting roles played by Giancarlo Esposito,
           Steve Buscemi, Paul Calderón, Janet Julian and Theresa Randle. It was released by Carolco Pictures
            (through New Line Cinema) on September 22, 1990, to generally positive reviews. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/King_of_New_York</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv10">
        <title>The French Connection</title>
        <director>William Friedkin</director>
        <length>104</length>
        <rating>7.7</rating>
        <year>1971</year>
        <image>../images/mv10.jpg</image>
        <alt>Man climbing stairs screaming after being shot by man at the bottom of the staircase with a pistol</alt>
        <blurb>The French Connection is a 1971 American crime action thriller film directed by William Friedkin.
         The screenplay, written by Ernest Tidyman, is based on Robin Moore's 1969 book of the same name.
          It tells the story of NYPD detectives Jimmy "Popeye" Doyle and Buddy "Cloudy" Russo, whose real-life counterparts 
          were Narcotics Detectives Eddie Egan and Sonny Grosso, in pursuit of wealthy French heroin smuggler Alain Charnier.
           The film stars Gene Hackman as Popeye, Roy Scheider as Cloudy, and Fernando Rey as Charnier. Tony Lo Bianco and 
           Marcel Bozzuffi also star. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_French_Connection_(film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv11">
        <title>The Untouchables</title>
        <director>Brian De Palma</director>
        <length>119</length>
        <rating>7.9</rating>
        <year>1987</year>
        <image>../images/mv11.jpg</image>
        <alt>In the foreground 5 police officers hold various guns, Al capone appears in a larger background image smoking a cigar </alt>
        <blurb>The Untouchables is a 1987 American crime film directed by Brian De Palma, produced by
         Art Linson, and written by David Mamet. The film is loosely based on the book of the same name (1957)
          and the real-life events it was based on, but most of its plot is fictionalized. The film stars Kevin Costner
          , Charles Martin Smith, Andy García, Robert De Niro (third collaboration between De Palma and De Niro,
           following 1968's Greetings and 1970's Hi, Mom!), and Sean Connery, and follows Eliot Ness (Costner) as he forms
            the Untouchables team to bring Al Capone (De Niro) to justice during Prohibition. The Grammy Award–nominated 
            score was composed by Ennio Morricone and features period music by Duke Ellington. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Untouchables_(film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv12">
        <title>New Jack City</title>
        <director>Mario Van Peebles</director>
        <length>100</length>
        <rating>6.6</rating>
        <year>1991</year>
        <image>../images/mv12.jpg</image>
        <alt>Three men stand in the foreground, in the background is a man with a cigarettte and a gun</alt>
        <blurb>New Jack City is a 1991 American action crime film based upon an original story and written by Thomas Lee Wright
         and Barry Michael Cooper, and directed by Mario Van Peebles in his feature film directorial debut as he also co-stars 
         in the film. The film stars Wesley Snipes, Ice-T, Allen Payne, Chris Rock, Mario Van Peebles, Judd Nelson, and Bill Cobbs.
          The film was released in the United States on March 8, 1991.</blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/New_Jack_City</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv13">
        <title>Mean Streets</title>
        <director>Martin Scorsese</director>
        <length>112</length>
        <rating>7.2</rating>
        <year>1973</year>
        <image>../images/mv13.jpg</image>
        <alt>An illustration of a cityscape with a hand holding a pistol shaped like a building</alt>
        <blurb>Mean Streets is a 1973 American crime film directed by Martin Scorsese and co-written by Scorsese and Mardik Martin.
         The film stars Harvey Keitel and Robert De Niro. It was released by Warner Bros. on October 2, 1973. De Niro won the 
         National Society of Film Critics and the New York Film Critics Circle award for Best Supporting Actor for his role as 
         "Johnny Boy" Civello. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mean_Streets</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv14">
        <title>Donnie Brasco</title>
        <director>Mike Newell</director>
        <length>127</length>
        <rating>7.7</rating>
        <year>1997</year>
        <image>../images/mv14.jpg</image>
        <alt>The view of a camera zoomed in on two men exiting some building</alt>
        <blurb>Donnie Brasco is a 1997 American crime drama film directed by Mike Newell, and starring Al Pacino
         and Johnny Depp. Michael Madsen, Bruno Kirby, James Russo, and Anne Heche appeared in supporting roles.
          The film, written by Paul Attanasio, is based on the 1988 nonfiction book Donnie Brasco: My Undercover Life
           in the Mafia by Joseph D. Pistone and Richard Woodley.</blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donnie_Brasco_(film)</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv15">
        <title>The Departed</title>
        <director>Martin Scorsese</director>
        <length>151</length>
        <rating>8.5</rating>
        <year>2006</year>
        <image>../images/mv15.jpg</image>
        <alt>The faces of three men, appearing in the background of the words The Departed</alt>
        <blurb>The Departed is a 2006 American epic crime thriller film directed by Martin Scorsese and written by William Monahan.
         It is both a remake of the 2002 Hong Kong film Infernal Affairs and also loosely based on the real-life Boston Winter Hill Gang;
          the character Colin Sullivan is based on the corrupt FBI agent John Connolly, while the character Frank Costello is based on 
          Irish-American gangster Whitey Bulger. The film stars Leonardo DiCaprio, Matt Damon, Jack Nicholson, and Mark Wahlberg, 
          with Martin Sheen, Ray Winstone, Vera Farmiga, and Alec Baldwin in supporting roles.</blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Departed</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv16">
        <title>Boyz N the Hood</title>
        <director>John Singleton</director>
        <length>112</length>
        <rating>7.8</rating>
        <year>1991</year>
        <image>../images/mv16.jpg</image>
        <alt>Two men leaning on a car, one man in the drivers seat looking backwards</alt>
        <blurb>Boyz n the Hood is a 1991 American coming-of-age hood drama film written and directed by John Singleton in his
         feature directorial debut. It stars Cuba Gooding Jr., Morris Chestnut, Ice Cube, Laurence Fishburne, Nia Long, Regina King, 
         and Angela Bassett. Boyz n the Hood follows Tre Styles (Gooding Jr.), who is sent to live with his father Furious Styles (Fishburne)
          in South Central Los Angeles, surrounded by the neighborhood's booming gang culture. The film's title is a double entendre:
           a play on the term boyhood and a reference to the 1987 Eazy-E rap song of the same name, written by Ice Cube. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Boyz_n_the_Hood</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv17">
        <title>Millers Crossing</title>
        <director>Ethan Coen</director>
        <length>115</length>
        <rating>7.7</rating>
        <year>1974</year>
        <image>../images/mv17.jpg</image>
        <alt>One man holds a gun in the woods, with a another man on his knees before him</alt>
        <blurb>Miller's Crossing is a 1990 American neo-noir gangster film written, directed and produced by the Coen brothers 
        and starring Gabriel Byrne, Marcia Gay Harden, John Turturro, Jon Polito, J. E. Freeman, and Albert Finney.
         The plot concerns a power struggle between two rival gangs and how the protagonist, Tom Reagan (Byrne), plays both sides against each other. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Miller%27s_Crossing</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv18">
        <title>The Usual Suspects</title>
        <director>Bryan Singer</director>
        <length>106</length>
        <rating>8.5</rating>
        <year>1995</year>
        <image>../images/mv18.jpg</image>
        <alt>Five men in a police lineup</alt>
        <blurb>The Usual Suspects is a 1995 drama film directed by Bryan Singer and written by Christopher McQuarrie. 
        It stars Stephen Baldwin, Gabriel Byrne, Benicio del Toro, Kevin Pollak, Chazz Palminteri, Pete Postlethwaite, and Kevin Spacey.
        The plot follows the interrogation of Roger "Verbal" Kint, a small-time con man, who is one of only two survivors 
        of a massacre and fire on a ship docked at the Port of Los Angeles.</blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Usual_Suspects</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv19">
        <title>Road To Perdition</title>
        <director>Sam Mendes</director>
        <length>117</length>
        <rating>6.4</rating>
        <year>2002</year>
        <image>../images/mv19.jpg</image>
        <alt>Three mens faces in the background,
         with a man holding a submachine gun, walking with a child in the foreground</alt>
        <blurb>Road to Perdition is a 2002 American crime drama film directed by Sam Mendes. The screenplay was adapted by David Self 
        from the graphic novel of the same name written by Max Allan Collins and illustrated by Richard Piers Rayner. The film stars Tom Hanks,
         Paul Newman (in his final live-action theatrical film acting role), Jude Law, and Daniel Craig. The plot takes place in 1931,
          during the Great Depression, following a mob enforcer and his son as they seek vengeance against a mobster who murdered the rest of their family. </blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Road_to_Perdition</link>
    </movie>
    <movie id="mv20">
        <title>Snatch</title>
        <director>Guy Ritchie</director>
        <length>102</length>
        <rating>8.2</rating>
        <year>2000</year>
        <image>../images/mv20.jpg</image>
        <alt>Six men in various types of clothing looking forward, one man holds a white dog on a leash</alt>
        <blurb>Snatch (stylized as snatch.) is a 2000 crime comedy film written and directed by Guy Ritchie, featuring an ensemble cast.
         Set in the London criminal underworld, the film contains two intertwined plots: one dealing with the search for a stolen diamond,
          the other with a small-time boxing promoter (Jason Statham) who finds himself under the thumb of a ruthless gangster (Alan Ford)
           who is ready and willing to have his subordinates carry out severe and sadistic acts of violence.</blurb>
        <link>https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Snatch_(film)</link>
    </movie>
</catalog>